MANAN PATEL

Toronto, ON · manan.patel@outlook.com · mananpatel.info

EDUCATION

University of Toronto

Toronto, ON

Bachelors of Science - Computer Science and Statistical Machine Learning

Sep 2013 - May 2019

EXPERIENCE

Environment & Climate Change Canada

 $Software\ Developer$

Toronto, ON

May 2017 - Present

- Developed WeatherCAN, the ECCC iOS weather application from concept to completion within 12 months in a small agile team.
- Created and maintained several important features such as real-time weather alert notifications,
 GPS tracked weather, CoreData management, and CoreGraphics charting. Am a key maintainer and liaison for the system architecture thought the life of the project.
- Created product generators that create weather data output for the use of the Canadian public. Data is produced and used in real-time operations across all national media and social outlets (such as CTV, Cp24, Global News, etc.) to disseminate daily weather information to Canadians.
- Created XML decoders used to parse incoming raw weather station data from BC marine buoys to a digital format for the use of the general public real-time API.

University of Toronto

Research Assistant

Toronto, ON Sept 2016 - Dec 2016

- Developed machine learning models of economic information about the countries of Peru and Canada to analyze the effect of trade policies on regional trade output.
- Created a database using Python based pre-processing techniques such as scraping and web-crawling. Then used R to formulate data into several different machine learning models to produce inferences about efficient trade policies.

Academic Advising & Career Centre - University of Toronto $Web\ Developer$

Toronto, ON May 2015 - Aug 2016

- Created an iOS application that allows passers-by to view and interact with dynamic web content to aid market the workshops and seminars offered by the AA&CC. Written in Swift which was combined with a back-end API to feed the data.
- Helped develop an internal ticket system and a social media plan that increased visits to the site by 30% while decreasing the amount of time taken for social media posts.

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

Python, Swift, Java, JavaScript, R, C, Ruby

Frameworks / Tools:

 $\operatorname{HTML}/\operatorname{CSS}, \operatorname{NodeJS}, \operatorname{React}, \operatorname{XML}, \operatorname{XCode}, \operatorname{Android} \operatorname{Studio}, \operatorname{Git}, \operatorname{Jenkins}$

ABOUT

I am a recent Computer Science graduate from UofT who is experienced in mobile and software development. I have prior experience building out iOS applications with Swift and research experience with machine learning and big data. Currently pursuing full-time/freelance work in the mobile space.

Projects

GroSaver Swift

Designed an iOS food saver mobile application that reminds you when your food is expiring. Reads a picture of a users grocery receipt and after certain periods of time reminds them when the types of food they bought are expected to go bad. Written in Swift and uses the Tesseract optical character recognition framework to parse the data from the images and APNS to send notifications. Currently trying to raise equity and grow the team to launch the product.

UiTube JavaScript, HTML, CSS

A chrome extension that changes the Youtube UI so that users can view the video, read comments, get the video info and related videos all in 1 page as well use night mode, auto disable annotations, etc.. Written using mainly JavaScipt, HTML, and CSS. Uses the Youtube and Google API's.